<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nuaNce</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nuaNce</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 11:44:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nigga What</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/nigga-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 11:44:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/nigga-what/</guid>
      <description>Weird Occurrences around these parts&amp;hellip;
[5:36 PM] — reayn.: hi [5:36 PM] Empress_Shizz: hi [5:36 PM] Empress_Shizz: how r u [5:36 PM] — reayn.: big sad [5:36 PM] — reayn.: but better [5:36 PM] — reayn.: wbu [5:36 PM] Empress_Shizz: why [5:37 PM] Empress_Shizz: u sad? [5:37 PM] — reayn.: bad ting happen last night [5:37 PM] — reayn.: but it ok [5:37 PM] Empress_Shizz: wut thing wana spill beans [5:37 PM] Empress_Shizz: like casereol [5:37 PM] — reayn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An In Depth Look at My Workflow</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/my-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:55:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/my-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I find most important when using a computer is effective
workflow management. Getting the most efficient setup and being able to do my
work as fast as possible while maintaining quality. In this post I will go over
some of the things I do in my setup to ensure that I have the most efficient
working environment possible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Stopped Using Windows</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/why-i-stopped-using-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:21:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/why-i-stopped-using-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before we begin, a confession, I used to really like Windows, I admit that it
was an &amp;ldquo;ignorant bliss&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, but back then I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know much
better. I used it often and started liking it even more when I started using
some of it&amp;rsquo;s slightly less obvious, &amp;ldquo;power user&amp;rdquo; oriented features, such as the
built in window management and multitasking capabilities. However, while I did
have quite a good time in my years using Windows, reality dawned on me in early
2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Git Pushes Less Annoying</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/use-git-fast-and-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 18:57:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/use-git-fast-and-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite annoyed by how much of a pain it can be to
do simple things with git. Even changes to your own repositories can take a
while with all of the adding and committing and then typing in your
credentials. Thankfully though, I have found ways to make git almost trivial to
use, now I barely have to enter more than one command for most tasks, here is
how I did it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I&#39;ve Been Reading</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 06:57:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/books/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of some books that I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying over the past year or so. I&amp;rsquo;ve divided them into categories and provided the best download links that I could find, and for series&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve given the link to the first book.
Series    Author Series Download (book 1)     Brandon Sanderson The Stormlight Archive The Way of Kings   Patrick Rothfuss The Kingkiller Chronicle The Name of The Wind   Robert Jordan The Wheel of Time The Eye of The World   Christopher Ruocchio Sun Eater Empire of Silence    &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of My Favorite Software</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a list of some software I find nice to use. A lot of these correlate with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/co1ncidence?tab=stars&#34;&gt;my stars on github&lt;/a&gt;, so be sure to check them out as well if you want some other nice things to use. My preferences with software usually boil down to:
  - It gets the job done
  - It&amp;rsquo;s smaller in size than similar software
  - It&amp;rsquo;s free and open source
  - It&amp;rsquo;s not overrated normie shit
  - And it integrates well with my workflow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with that out of the way, here is the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and CLI, a 101</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/linux-and-cli-a-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 14:15:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/linux-and-cli-a-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started with Linux, and especially the command line, It was
difficult to find a truly optimal and comprehensive guide to everything I
needed to know. While most tutorials were decent and gave me a good starting
point, they usually provided insufficient information or didn&amp;rsquo;t showcase the
most optimal commands and strategies. I am making this list as more of a dump
for all of the things that I have learned about Linux and the Command Line so
far. While my knowledge isn&amp;rsquo;t too much compared to some, I like to think that I
know something. So without further ado, here is my guide to help boost you up
in the Linux elitist ladder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Top 10 Best Looking Cars</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/top-10-best-looking-cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 15:58:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/top-10-best-looking-cars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked cars and have been reading automotive journalism for many
years now. While many things come into play when considering a vehicle to buy,
none, in my opinion, are as important as how good your car looks. So I&amp;rsquo;ve
compiled a list of what I think are the best looking cars that I have ever
seen. Expect this list to vary over time, however, since it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me not
to change my mind about these things all the time: \course{Nigger Course}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Rices</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</guid>
      <description>Here are all most of the Rices that I have made on my computer over the last few months, some are pretty similar to each other but I put them in here anyway. If you would like to try some of my configs for yourself, visit my dotless files repository.
&amp;nbsp;
Itai 
Heads and Tails 
The Nomad 
Deja Vu 
Bliss v2 
The Mountaineer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 23:44:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m just a lost windrunner who spends too much of his time, well, wasting it. Most of what I do in those moments ends up leaving me with fewer and fewer friends as the days go by. But it&amp;rsquo;s fine, it&amp;rsquo;s all for the greater good, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Anyhow, you&amp;rsquo;ll find out plenty about happens in those hours on this website anyway, so no need to talk about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>