<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nuaNce&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nuaNce&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 18:57:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Git Pushes Less Annoying</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/use-git-fast-and-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 18:57:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/use-git-fast-and-easy/</guid>
      <description>For a long time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite annoyed by how much of a pain it can be to do simple things with git. Even changes to your own repositories can take a while with all of the adding and committing and then typing in your credentials. Thankfully though, I have found ways to make git almost trivial to use, now I barely have to enter more than one command for most tasks, here is how I did it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Stopped Using Windows</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/why-i-stopped-using-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:21:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/why-i-stopped-using-windows/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin, a confession, I used to really like Windows, I admit that it was an &amp;ldquo;ignorant bliss&amp;rdquo; kind of thing, but back then I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know much better. I used it often and started liking it even more when I began using some of it&amp;rsquo;s more hidden, &amp;ldquo;power user oriented&amp;rdquo; features, such as the built in window management and multitasking capabilities. And while I did have quite a good time in my years using Windows, reality dawned on me in early 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I&#39;ve Been Reading</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 06:57:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/books/</guid>
      <description>Series    Author Series Download (book 1)     Brandon Sanderson The Stormlight Archive The Way of Kings   Patrick Rothfuss The Kingkiller Chronicle The Name of The Wind   Robert Jordan The Wheel of Time The Eye of The World   Christopher Ruocchio Sun Eater Empire of Silence     Singles (fiction)    Author Book Download     Brandon Sanderson Elantris EPUB   Stephen King Doctor Sleep PDF   John Steinbeck The Grapes of Wrath PDF   Brandon Sanderson Warbreaker EPUB     Singles (non-fiction)    Author Book Download     Saif&amp;rsquo; ur-Rahman Mubarakpuri The Sealed Nectar EPUB   Jake Knapp and John Zeratsky Make Time PDF   Graham Alcott How to be a Productivity Ninja EPUB   Michael Bazzel Open Source Intelligence PDF   Tim Ferriss Tribe of Mentors TOR     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of My Favorite Software</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of some software I find nice to use, most are pretty minimal as well:
         cfm Simple and fast terminal file manager   maim Extremely powerful CLI screenshot tool   SXIV &amp;ldquo;Simple X Image Viewer&amp;rdquo;   giph Customizable and easy to use GIF recorder   birch Freenode IRC client written in bash   farge Finally a lightweight CLI colorpicker   ungoogled-chromium Browse safely and privately, no compromises   ST Simple Terminal   shfm Terminal file browser written in bash   epy Terminal based Ebook reader   wpm Command line typing test   cchat-gtk GTK+ frontend for cchat&amp;rsquo;s    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and CLI, a 101</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/bash-basics-for-nubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 14:15:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/bash-basics-for-nubs/</guid>
      <description>When I first started with Linux, and especially the command line, It was difficult to find a truly optimal and comprehensive guide to these things. While most tutorials were nice and gave me a good starting point, they usually provided inefficient information or didn&amp;rsquo;t showcase the most optimal commands/strategies. I am making this list as more of a dump for all of the things that I have learned about bash so far, which isn&amp;rsquo;t too much compared to some but I like to think that I know something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Top 10 Best Looking Cars</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/top-10-best-looking-cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 15:58:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/top-10-best-looking-cars/</guid>
      <description>Mercedes AMG GT-R One of the only cars in recent times to really pose a threat to the sales of the 911, the GT does a good job of representing a similar muscular and round look while also adhering to the aesthetic of it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor, the SLS AMG.
Datsun 240z Fairlady One of the most well-known sports cars of it&amp;rsquo;s time and now a JDM legend, the amount of things that have been done to the Datsun are insane, here is NightRide&amp;rsquo;s iteration of the vehicle, one of the best looking ones I&amp;rsquo;ve found:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Linux Rices</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</guid>
      <description>Current rice,  Gallery of Older Rices,  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 23:44:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Minimalism is not the lack of something, but instead the perfect amount of it&amp;rdquo;
 Just a lost windrunner who spends too much his time wasting it, mostly due to my obsession with Linux and ricing. Along with, of course, a good peach and chocolate covered almonds, nothing wastes time like those do.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of the Fjords of Norway but recently discovered the beauty of places like Iceland and Baffin Island, both of which are making my bucket list seem quite expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>