<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:59:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few of My Favorite Monospaced Fonts</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/monospaced-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:59:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/monospaced-fonts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a bit of an exaggerated font collection, most likely because I could never really decide on a single one. I do, however, have quite a few that I like more than others, here are some of them:
Bergen Mono Roboto Mono Input Mono Apercu PT Mono Operator Mono Alma Mono JetBrains Mono Space Mono Overpass Mono Liberation Mono Bront IBM Plex Mono DM Mono DejaVu Sans Mono Source Code Pro </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Shell Scripts I&#39;ve Found Handy</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:12:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-scripts/</guid>
      <description>This post will most likely get updated as time goes by
 Vibe: I had used mpd and ncmpcpp for my music for a long time now, but decided to switch to mpv for the simplicity, and to make things even easier, I wrote this script, which shuffles all of the music files in the chosen directory and plays them in a terminal window, with album art in it&amp;rsquo;s own small, separate window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of My Favorite Software</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of some software I find nice to use:
   Software Description     cfm Simple and fast terminal file manager   maim Extremely powerful CLI screenshot tool   SXIV &amp;ldquo;Simple X Image Viewer&amp;rdquo;   giph Customizable and easy to use GIF recorder   birch Freenode IRC client written in bash   farge Finally a lightweight CLI colorpicker   ungoogled-chromium Browse safely and privately, no compromises   ST Simple Terminal   shfm Terminal file browser written in bash   epy Terminal based Ebook reader   wpm Command line typing test   cchat-gtk GTK+ frontend for cchat&amp;rsquo;s    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Linux Rices</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</guid>
      <description>Morning Coffee. Safe and Sound. Bloated Minimalism. Misty Mountain. Function &amp;gt; Form. Contempt. One With The Mountain. Is One Rose Enough? IceBerg. Attention to Detail. Bliss v1.5 Polka. GMK Dots. :bleedingeyes: Don&amp;rsquo;t Ask. Colors of Seoul Mediocre. A Night in Paris. Pop of Red. Bliss. Sans of Time. Clarity. Windows 98 Gloomy Nights. Warm and Sweet. Serenity. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>