<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:59:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few of My Favorite Monospaced Fonts</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/monospaced-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:59:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/monospaced-fonts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a bit of an exaggerated font collection, most likely because I could never really decide on a single one. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided instead to make a list of all the ones that I (semi-regularly) switch around between. These screenshots are taken using the alacritty terminal at 800px width and 11px font size. This consistency allows for easier distinction between the line spacing and font size differences seen here. I have also nudged the line height by a bit to make the screenshots appear a bit less crowded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Shell Scripts I&#39;ve Found Handy</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:12:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-scripts/</guid>
      <description>This post will most likely get updated as time goes by
 Vibe: I had used mpd and ncmpcpp for my music for a long time now, but decided to switch to mpv for the simplicity, and to make things even easier, I wrote this script, which shuffles all of the music files in the chosen directory and plays them in a terminal window, with album art in it&amp;rsquo;s own small, separate window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of My Favorite Software</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of some software I find nice to use:
   Software Description     giph Customizable and easy to use GIF recorder   maim Extremely powerful CLI screenshot tool   SXIV &amp;ldquo;Simple X Image Viewer&amp;rdquo;   birch Freenode IRC client written in bash   farge Simple Colorpicker written in bash   ungoogled-chromium Browse safely and google-free, no compromises   ST Simple Terminal   shfm Terminal file browser written in posix shell   cchat-gtk GTK+ frontend for cchat   cfm Simple and fast terminal file manager   epy Terminal based Ebook reader   wpm Command line typing test    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Linux Rices</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</guid>
      <description>Here are all most of the Rices that I have made on my computer over the last few months, some are pretty similar to each other but I put them in here anyway. If you would like to try some of my configs for yourself, visit my dotless files repository.
 Dark Inside.  The Mountaineer.  Morning Coffee.  Safe and Sound.  Bloated Minimalism.  Function &amp;gt; Form.  Contempt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>