<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/</link>
    <description>nuaNce&#39;s blog (Showcase)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Openbox Rice</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/my-openbox-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/my-openbox-rice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/7b8q0jN.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above you can see a pretty complete screenshot of my openbox rice. I like to go for a kinda comfy, retro feels with my rices and like to avoid too many vivid colors. My polybar is also kept to a minimal, as to keep my (fairly) weak laptop from being under too much stress. One of my main goals with this rice was to minimize resource usage. I managed to accomplish this very well, with &lt;strong&gt;my ram usage after a fresh boot and with mpd running being only 280mb.&lt;/strong&gt; This is without consequence as well, I have the cupsd daemon running to manage print jobs, and with networkmanager running as well. One of my main goals with this system was to have something that not only was beautiful and efficient, but also usable in every scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/38b0Tm8.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of my rice I am really proud of is integrating a keyboard based workflow into openbox, I have the ability move, resize, and snap windows all with the keyboard, see this gif for more a more clear explanation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/GKp4kB9.gif&#34; alt=&#34;gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One may wonder, however, why I don&amp;rsquo;t just use a tiling window manager. There is one main reason, Windows becoming fullscreen automatically gets really annoying after a while, and I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of the straight-edge aesthetic in most tiling window managers. Another, more personal reason, is that I really like the customizability and lightness of openbox, and, most importantly, the right-click menu, which allows me to quickly access my favorite programs and some mpd controls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/KdZhCuI.gif&#34; alt=&#34;gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Here are some more screenshots of my setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/xtqNzxM.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imgur.com/3k3w8Wb.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/jyNVWZD.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks for sticking with me through this showcase, I hope you enjoyed it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>