<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Showcase on nuaNce&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:12:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/showcase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Shell Scripts I&#39;ve Found Handy</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:12:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-scripts/</guid>
      <description>This post is very messy and mostly made for testing code blocks.
 Vibe: I had used mpd and ncmpcpp for my music for a long time now, but decided to switch to mpv for the simplicity, and to make things even easier, I wrote this script, which shuffles all of the music files in the chosen directory and plays them in a terminal window, with album art in it&amp;rsquo;s own small, separate window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of My Favorite Software</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:43:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/some-cool-software/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of some software I find nice to use:
   Software Description     dash Fast and powerful POSIX shell   giph Customizable and easy to use GIF recorder   maim Extremely powerful CLI screenshot tool   mpv Simple yet featureful CLI media player   SXIV &amp;ldquo;Simple X Image Viewer&amp;rdquo;   birch Freenode IRC client written in bash   herbe Simple, yet DBus free notifications   farge Simple Colorpicker written in bash   ungoogled-chromium Browse safely and Google-free, no compromises   ST Simple Terminal   scr Super Crappy SCReenshot SCRipt for Sound Cloud Rappers   vimtex Make LaTeX in Vim a breeze to edit   ale A complete syntax checker and linter for Vim   neovim Objectively the best editor   shfm Terminal file browser written in posix shell   KISS Linux An independent Linux Distro focused on simplicity   cfm Simple and fast terminal file manager   epy Terminal based Ebook reader   PDF Viewer Plus The best mobile PDF viewer there is   ripcord Not great, but it&amp;rsquo;s a minimal discord client   doas Simple and light sudo replacement   wpm Command line typing test   monkey-type Clean, fun, and minimal typing test   wmutils Very extensible set of WM utilities   0x0 Effective, No-Bullshit file hosting    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Linux Rices</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/rices/</guid>
      <description>Here are all most of the Rices that I have made on my computer over the last few months, some are pretty similar to each other but I put them in here anyway. If you would like to try some of my configs for yourself, visit my dotless files repository.
 Bliss v2.  Dark Inside.  The Mountaineer.  Morning Coffee.  Safe and Sound.  Bloated Minimalism.  Function &amp;gt; Form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>