<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guide on nuaNce&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guide on nuaNce&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 18:57:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://co1ncidence.github.io/tags/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Git Pushes Less Annoying</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/use-git-fast-and-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 18:57:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/use-git-fast-and-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite annoyed by how much of a pain it can be to do simple things with git. Even changes to your own repositories can take a while with all of the adding and committing and then typing in your credentials. Thankfully though, I have found ways to make git almost trivial to use, now I barely have to enter more than one command for most tasks, here is how I did it:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and CLI, a 101</title>
      <link>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/linux-and-cli-a-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 14:15:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://co1ncidence.github.io/posts/linux-and-cli-a-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started with Linux, and especially the command line, It was difficult to find a truly optimal and comprehensive guide to everything I needed to know. While most tutorials were decent and gave me a good starting point, they usually provided insufficient information or didn&amp;rsquo;t showcase the most optimal commands and strategies. I am making this list as more of a dump for all of the things that I have learned about Linux and the Command Line so far. While my knowledge isn&amp;rsquo;t too much compared to some, I like to think that I know something. So without further ado, here is my guide to help boost you up in the Linux elitist ladder:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>